Guide to the Iron Clad Agreement Records, 1973-1989 CTC.1990.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Iron Clad Agreement Records
1973-1989
CTC.1990.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
18.5 linear feet (27 boxes)
The Iron Clad Agreement theatre company integrated historical research and live theatre. The group operated in Pittsburgh and New York City from 1976 till 1985. The collection contains operational files, correspondence, scripts, photographs, slides, audio and audio/visual recordings relating to the company's operation.
Iron Clad Agreement (Theatrical company).
Previous Citation
Iron Clad Agreement Records, 1973-1989, CTC.1990.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Iron Clad Agreement Records, 1975-1985, CTC.22, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Gift of Julia Royall, Iron Clad Agreement Producer, 1990. Additional materials were donated by Julia Royall in 2015.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
The Iron Clad Agreement materials are arranged into seven series.
Series I. Operational Files, 1973-1986
Series II. Playscripts, 1976-1989
Series III. Photographs, 1976-1982
Series IV. Slides, 1977-1981
Series V. Audio Recordings, 1975-1984
Series VI. Audio/Visual Recordings, 1977-1982
Series VII. Oversized and Ephemera, 1976-1981
Scope and Content Notes
The Iron Clad Agreement records are arranged into seven series. The first is a group of operational files that are arranged alphabetically. Series II is a complete set of play scripts for all the productions that the Iron Clad Agreement performed. All of these play scripts are cross-referenced in the Curtis Play script and Acting Edition collection binder. These first two series make up the bulk of the collection. The remaining series III-VII are photographs, slides, audio recordings, video recordings, and oversized/ephemera, respectively. Please note that the Iron Clad Agreement founder Julia Royall is citied throughout the finding aid as Julia Swoyer, her name at the time.
History
The Iron Clad Agreement was founded in Pittsburgh in 1976 by Julia Royall and K. Wilson Hutton as a traveling forum for producing original theatre productions. Their work integrated historical research and live theatre emphasizing the performer as the most portable element of theatre. The Iron Clad Agreement sought to explore the age of America's Industrial Revolution--its inventors, workers, feminists, and labor leaders. Scripts and songs were written specifically for or by the company in the unique Iron Clad style, somewhere between vaudeville and documentary drama. The group performed extensively in a variety of non-traditional theatre settings for audiences of all ages and economic backgrounds.
Besides performances, the company's services included post-performance discussions; artistic and administrative internships; and workshops in acting, directing, movement, speech and voice. In 1981, the company moved their central base of operation to New York City with live history-oriented theatre productions and projects including the Eastern U.S., U.K. and Hong Kong. In addition to several Pittsburgh radio productions, they ventured into some television and film around the same thematic focus.
Major premiers included Edison at Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, NYC; Virgins and Dynamos at The Royal Society of Arts, London; and The Gilded Age of Invention at the Edinburgh International Festival, Scotland. The company was also featured on the Creativity with Bill Moyers television series and the Smithsonian Institution's film Mr. Edison and his Amazing Invention Factories. The company continued its unique style of blending history with theatre until ceasing major operations in 1985. Its final production, Hasta Cuando? for the National Conference of Puerto Rican Women under the auspices of We the People 2000, occurred in 1987.
Adams, Henry, 1838-1918; Barnum, P.T. (Phineas Taylor), 1810-1891; Burbank, Luther, 1849-1926; Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919; Chesnut, Mary Boykin Miller, 1823-1886; Eastman, George, 1854-1932; Edinburgh International Festival.; Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931 -- Drama; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947; Grimké, Angelina Emily, 1805-1879; Grimké, Sarah Moore, 1792-1873; Guggenheim, Solomon R. (Solomon Robert), 1861-1949; Heinz, H. J. (Henry John), 1844-1919; Hutton, Wilson; Iron Clad Agreement (Theatrical company).; Lee, Muna, 1895-1965; Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts.; Meyers, Larry John; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964; Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain).; Royall, Julia; Westinghouse, George, 1846-1914; Whitney, Eli, 1765-1825; Audiocassettes; Audiotapes; Creativity with Bill Moyers; Industrial revolution -- Drama; Inventors -- Drama; Mr. Edison and his amazing invention factories (Motion picture); Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Performing arts -- United States; Photographs; Scripts (Documents); Slides (Photographs); Theater; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Theater -- United States; Video recordings; Videocassettes; Videotapes
- Operational Files, 1973-1986; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  These files contain the daily business files, correspondence, minutes, contracts, schedules, etc. for the operation of the organization. They are arranged alphabetically.
  - Actor's Equity Association, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Actor Training (Folder 2)
  - Alliance of Pittsburgh Theatres, 1979-1981 (Folder 3)
  - Arts Management, 1978-1980 (Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors - Correspondence, 1976-1986 (Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors - General, 1977-1986 (Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes, 1976-1985 (Folder 7)
  - Bookings - Allegheny Intermediate Unit, 1978-1980 (Folder 8-9)
  - Bookings - Allegheny Intermediate Unit Final Report to the Howard Heinz Endowment, 1979-1980 (Folder 10)
  - Bookings - Allegheny Intermediate Unit, Presentation J, 1980-1981 (Folder 11)
  - Bookings - American Wind Symphony, Summer, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bookings - Art/Work, 1980-1981 (Folder 2)
  - Bookings - Booking Contract (Folder 3)
  - Bookings - Carnegie Institute/Blythe, 1981 (Folder 4)
  - Bookings - City-County, 1980 (Folder 5)
  - Bookings - Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Folder 6)
  - Bookings - Edinburgh, 1976-1979 (Folder 7)
  - Bookings - Edison (Past Bookings), 1979-1980 (Folder 8)
  - Bookings - Father K, New York Showcase, 1979-1980 (Folder 9)
  - Bookings - Father K (Past Bookings), 1979-1980 (Folder 10)
  - Bookings - Festivals and Conferences, 1976-1978 (Folder 11)
  - Bookings - 57 By Two/ Shiver Me Timbers, 1975-1980 (Folder 12)
  - Bookings - Gateway to Music, 1979-1981 (Folder 13)
  - Bookings - Gilded Age (Past Gigs in Pittsburgh Area), 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bookings - Gilded Age (Past Gigs on tour), 1977-1979 (Folder 2)
  - Bookings - Interchangeable Parts, 1979-81 (Folder 3)
  - Bookings - Lincoln Center, 1979-1983 (Folder 4)
  - Bookings - Maps, Handouts, Memorabilia (Folder 5)
  - Bookings - Mid-Atlantic, 1980-1982 (Folder 6)
  - Bookings - My Dear Sisters, 1980 (Folder 7)
  - Bookings - New York Showcase, 1980-1981 (Folder 8)
  - Bookings - Notes, Agendas, Calendars, 1978-1979 (Folder 9)
  - Bookings - Ourselves Alone, 1980-1981 (Folder 10)
  - Bookings - Out of This Furnace, 1977-1979 (Folder 11)
  - Bookings - Past Gigs, 1976-1980 (Folder 12)
  - Bookings - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, Showcase, 1978 (Folder 13)
  - Bookings - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, Touring Seminar, 1981 (Folder 14)
  - Bookings - Performance Lists, 1976-1982 (Folder 15)
  - Bookings - Pittsburgh Symphony, 1977-1979 (Folder 16)
  - Bookings - Scene Lists, Play Structures, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bookings - T.A.P. Showcase, Conference and Touring Project, 1977-1978 (Folder 2)
  - Bookings - T.A.P. Showcase and Pilot Touring Project, Fall 1978-Spring 1979 (Folder 3)
  - Bookings - T.A.P. Conference and Showcase, 1979-1980 (Folder 4)
  - Bookings - Tour Sheets, 1981 (Folder 5)
  - Bookings - Toymakers, 1981 (Folder 6)
  - Bright Star Films, 1980-1985 (Folder 7)
  - Budgets, 1976-1981 (Folder 8)
  - Business Committee of the Arts, 1976-1980 (Folder 9)
  - California Labor History, 1980-1982 (Folder 10)
  - Carlow College, 1980-1981 (Folder 11)
  - Center for Entrepreneurial Development, Carnegie Mellon, 1976-1982 (Folder 12)
  - Charter and By-Laws, 1976-1981 (Folder 13)
  - Cititrust, 1981-1983 (Folder 14)
  - Citizens for the Arts in Pennsylvania, 1979-1981 (Folder 15)
  - Citizens for the Arts in Pennsylvania, Pittsburgh Regional Committee, 1976-1978 (Folder 16)
  - Collaborative for the Arts in Pittsburgh Education, 1978-1979 (Folder 17)
  - Connecticut Humanities Council, 1983 (Folder 18)
  - Connecticut Oral History - Quinebaug, 1984 (Folder 19)
  - Contracts, 1977-1982 (Folder 20)
  - Copyrights, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Fan Mail, 1976-1982 (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Inventors and Companies, 1976-1978 (Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1978-1979 (Folder 4)
  - David Demarest - Center for Regional Studies, 1977-1982 (Folder 5)
  - David Demarest - Coke Region Article, 1982 (Folder 6)
  - David Demarest - Pittsburgh Regional Curriculum, 1980 (Folder 7)
  - David Demarest - Thomas Bell Collection, Carnegie Mellon, 1977-1983 (Folder 8)
  - David Demarest - Three Generations of Ethnicity, 1978-1979 (Folder 9)
  - David Demarest - Kazincy, Father Adalbert ( Father K), Fall 1979 (Folder 10)
  - DuArt Films, 1983 (Folder 11)
  - Echoes in America - Actor's Equity Association, 1983-1984 (Folder 12)
  - Echoes in America - Budget (Folder 13)
  - Echoes in America - Connecticut (Including Connecticut Humanities Council), 1982-1984 (Folder 14)
  - Echoes in America - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Folder 15)
  - Echoes in America - Exhibit, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Echoes in America - Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1983-1984 (Folder 2)
  - Echoes in America - Legal, 1984 (Folder 3)
  - Echoes in America - Major Road Theatre Company, 1983-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Echoes in America - New York City, 1982-1984 (Folder 5)
  - Echoes in America - Newspaper, 1982-1984 (Folder 6)
  - Echoes in America - North Carolina (including North Carolina Humanities Council), 1981-1984 (Folder 7)
  - Echoes in America - Office of Technology Assessment, 1983-1984 (Folder 8)
  - Echoes in America - Original Copies, Forms, Releases, etc., 1983-1984 (Folder 9)
  - Echoes in America - Press Agent, 1983-1984 (Folder 10)
  - Echoes in America - Press materials and Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Folder 11)
  - Echoes in America - Rhode Island, 1983-1984 (Folder 12)
  - Echoes in America - South Carolina, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Echoes in America - South Carolina Educational Television, 1983 (Folder 2)
  - Echoes in America - State Schedules, 1984 (Folder 3)
  - Father K - Resource Material, 1977-1980 (Folder 4)
  - Federal Surplus Personal Property Donation Program, 1977-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Filmmaking - Media, 1977-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Filmmaking - Warner Cable, 1979 (Folder 7)
  - Financial Statements, September 1978-August 1979 (Folder 8)
  - Financial Statements, September 1979-August 1980 (Folder 9)
  - Financial Statements, September 1980-August 1981 (Folder 10)
  - Financial Statements, September 1981-August 1982 (Folder 11)
  - Financial Statements, September 1982-August 1983 (Folder 12)
  - Financial Statements, September 1983-August 1984 (Folder 13)
  - Funding - CETA, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Funding - Connecticut Humanities Council/Corporate, 1978-1981 (Folder 3)
  - Funding - Corporate Proposal, 1977-1978 (Folder 4)
  - Funding - Corporate Proposal, 1978 (Folder 5)
  - Funding - Corporate Proposal, 1978-1979 (Folder 6)
  - Funding - Corporate Proposal, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Funding - Corporate Proposal, 1980-1981 (Folder 2)
  - Funding - Shelby Collom Davis Project, 1977-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Funding - Ethnic Societies, 1978-1979 (Folder 4)
  - Funding - Ford Foundation, 1977-1981 (Folder 5)
  - Funding - Heinz Endowment/Pittsburgh Foundation, 1977-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Funding - Junior League, 1978 (Folder 7)
  - Funding - National Endowment for the Arts/ Expansion Arts, 1979-1981 (Folder 8)
  - Funding - National Endowment for the Arts/Small Professional Theatres, 1979-1981 (Folder 9)
  - Funding - National Science Foundation, 1973, 1978-1980 (Folder 10)
  - Funding - Neighborhood Assistance, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Funding - Neighborhood Assistance, 1978-1979 (Folder 2)
  - Funding - North Carolina Humanities Council, 1979-1981 (Folder 3)
  - Funding - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, 1977-1981 (Folder 4)
  - Funding - Public Committee for the Humanities in Pennsylvania, 1980-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Funding - South Carolina Committee for the Humanities, 1979-1981 (Folder 6)
  - Funding - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities, 1979-1981 (Folder 7)
  - Funding - Wean Foundation, 1982-1986 (Folder 8)
  - Gilded Age of Invention - Television Package, 1982-1986 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Gilded Age of Invention - Television Treatment, 1982-1984 (Folder 2)
  - Govt. Owned Apples - Lovelace Theatre, 1977-1979 (Folder 3)
  - Grimke Sisters - General, 1979-1986 (Folder 4)
  - Guest Book, 1979-1984 (Folder 5)
  - Handicapped, 1980 (Folder 6)
  - The Hard Rock Show (Rhode Island Feminist Theatre), 1985 (Folder 7)
  - Hong Kong - Arts Center, 1984-1985 (Folder 8)
  - Hong Kong - Center for the Progress of the Peoples, 1981-1984 (Folder 9)
  - Hong Kong - Concept Papers, 1984 (Folder 10)
  - Hong Kong - Contracts, 1982-1983 (Folder 11)
  - Hong Kong - Correspondence, 1984 (Folder 12)
  - Hong Kong - Final Report, 1984 (Folder 13)
  - Hong Kong - International Theatre Institute, 1984 (Folder 14)
  - Hong Kong - Workshops, 1984 (Folder 15)
  - Idaho Labor History, 1974- 1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Ideas for Plays, 1966-1981 (Folder 2)
  - Insurance - Blue Cross, 1978-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Insurance - Hartford, 1979-1985 (Folder 4)
  - Intern, 1978-1979 (Folder 5)
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1976-1985 (Folder 6)
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1979-1983 (Folder 7)
  - Kingfisher Films, 1981-1982 (Folder 8)
  - Labor History Cassettes (Folder 9)
  - Labor - General Information, 1974, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Labor - Resource Material (Pittsburgh), 1977 (Folder 2)
  - Movietone, 1983 (Folder 3)
  - Neighborhood Assistance Summer Program - Application Forms (Folder 4)
  - Office and Phone Information, 1981 (Folder 5)
  - Out of This Furnace - Contracts, 1977-1979 (Folder 6)
  - Out of This Furnace - Correspondence (College, USW, and Slovak World Congress), 1978-1979 (Folder 7)
  - Out of This Furnace - Correspondence (General), 1976-1981 (Folder 8)
  - Out of This Furnace - Designs, 1977-1978 (Folder 9)
  - Out of This Furnace - Funding Proposals, 1977-1979 (Folder 10)
  - Out of This Furnace - Laurel Group, 1978-1983 (Folder 11)
  - Out of This Furnace - New York Showcase, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Out of This Furnace - PR, 1977 (Folder 2)
  - Out of This Furnace - Schedules and Lists, 1978 (Folder 3)
  - Paine Webber, 1981-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Palmer Associates, 1982-1984 (Folder 5)
  - Press - Bios, 1978-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Press - Brochure Copy, 1978 (Folder 7)
  - Press - Edison, 1979-1980 (Folder 8)
  - Press - Father K, 1979-1980 (Folder 9)
  - Press - General, 1976-1978 (Folder 10)
  - Press - General, Spring 1978-Summer 1979 (Folder 11)
  - Press - General, Fall 1979-Summer 1980 (Folder 12)
  - Press - General, 1980-1981 (Folder 13)
  - Press - Grimke and Heinz, 1980 (Folder 14)
  - Press - Lists, 1975-1979 (Folder 15)
  - Press - Magazines and Newsletters, 1976-1979 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Press - Mailing Lists, 1977-1980 (Folder 2-3)
  - Press - Minds in Motion Tour, 1980-1981 (Folder 4)
  - Press - Press Pack Originals, 1980-1981 (Folder 5)
  - Press - Early Releases and Manifestos, 1976-1978 (Folder 6)
  - Press - Releases (Originals), 1980-1981 (Folder 7)
  - Press - Releases, 1978-1980 (Folder 8)
  - Press - Out of This Furnace, 1977-1979 (Folder 9)
  - Programs (Incomplete), 1976-1981 (Folder 10)
  - Promotional Material - Flyers, newsletter, etc., 1976-1981 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Puerto Rico - American Federation of Radio and Television Artists, 1981 (Folder 2)
  - Puerto Rico - American Wind Symphony, 1980-1982 (Folder 3)
  - Puerto Rico - Arts Festival, October 1982 (Folder 4)
  - Puerto Rico - Barbara Damashek, 1981-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rico - Caribbean/Sea-Change, 1983-1986 (Folder 6)
  - Puerto Rico - Connecticut Humanities Council, 1980-1983 (Folder 7)
  - Puerto Rico - Contracts, 1981-1983 (Folder 8)
  - Puerto Rico - Corporations, 1981-1983 (Folder 9)
  - Puerto Rico - Early Evolution of Sea-Change Project, 1981-1982 (Folder 10)
  - Puerto Rico - Florida Humanities, 1981 (Folder 11)
  - Puerto Rico - Foundations, 1980-1983 (Folder 12)
  - Puerto Rico - Housing, 1981-1982 (Folder 13)
  - Puerto Rico - Humanities, 1966-1967, 1970, 1977-1985 (Folder 14)
  - Puerto Rico - Institute of Film and Television, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Puerto Rico - Massachusetts, 1982 (Folder 2)
  - Puerto Rico - Mississippi Humanities, 1981-1982 (Folder 3)
  - Puerto Rico - MUNA Notes, 1981 (Folder 4)
  - Puerto Rico - MUNA Proposal, 1980-1981 (Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rico - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1982 (Folder 6)
  - Puerto Rico - New Jersey Humanities, 1981-1982 (Folder 7)
  - Puerto Rico - New York Humanities, 1981-1982 (Folder 8)
  - Puerto Rico - Oklahoma Humanities, 1981-1982 (Folder 9)
  - Puerto Rico - Research, 1981-1983 (Folder 10)
  - Puerto Rico - Sea-Change R&D Report, 1982-1983 (Folder 11)
  - Puerto Rico - South Carolina Committee for the Humanities, 1981-1982 (Folder 12)
  - Radio - The Blind, 1979-1980 (Folder 13)
  - Radio - Colleges, 1979-1980 (Folder 14)
  - Radio - Contacts, Radio Stations, Ideas, etc., 1978-1981 (Folder 15)
  - Radio - General Proposal, 1979 (Folder 16)
  - Radio - National Federation of Community Broadcasters, 1978-1981 (Folder 17)
  - Radio - National Public Radio, 1979-1981 (Folder 18)
  - Radio - Public Committee for the Humanities in Pennsylvania, 1978-1979 (Folder 19)
  - Radio - Public Radio Cooperative, 1980-1981 (Folder 20)
  - Radio - Threads, 1979-1980 (Folder 21)
  - Radio - Union Sponsorship, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Radio - WYEP, 1976-1977 (Folder 2)
  - Radio - ZBS, 1979-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Rhode Island - Oral History (Rhode Island Feminist Theatre), 1984-1985 (Folder 4)
  - Sales Tax - Exemption, 1976, 1979-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Sales Tax - Connecticut, 1981-1985 (Folder 6)
  - Shrum, Paul - Certified Public Accountant, 1979-1981 (Folder 7)
  - Smithsonian Film, 1978-1979 (Folder 8)
  - South Carolina - Oral History (St. Helena), 1981, 1984-1987 (Folder 9)
  - Swissvale, 1978-1981 (Folder 10)
  - Swissvale Arts Center, 1979-1981 (Folder 11)
  - Technology and Industry - General Information, 1976-1980 (Folder 12)
  - Textile Project - Research and Development, 1981-1984 (Folder 13)
  - Theatre Association of Pennsylvania, 1979-1980 (Folder 14)
  - Theatre Communications Group, 1978-1981 (Folder 15)
  - Thread/Work, 1980-1986, 1990 (Folder 16)
  - Touring Book, 1979-1982 (Folder 17)
  - Unemployment Insurance - Connecticut, 1982-1984 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Unemployment Insurance - Pennsylvania, 1982-1983 (Folder 2)
  - Van, 1984 (Folder 3)
  - Vanka Murals, 1980-1983 (Folder 4)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Budget (England), 1981 (Folder 5)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Correspondence (England), 1981 (Folder 6)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Final Report (England), 1981 (Folder 7)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Funding (England), 1981 (Folder 8)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Jerry James (England), 1981 (Folder 9)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Major Road Theatre Company (England), 1981 (Folder 10)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Notes (England), 1981 (Folder 11)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Publicity Materials (England), 1981 (Folder 12)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Sponsors (England), 1981 (Folder 13)
  - Virgins and Dynamos - Travel (England), 1981 (Folder 14)
  - Westinghouse Videotape, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Youngstown, 1979-1982 (Folder 2-3)
- Playscripts, 1976-1989; II.
  This is a complete run of scripts from all produced plays, most have multiple revisions included. All scripts also have been indexed in CTC's AE Inventory. The scripts are listed alphabetically by its title, then the author is listed, and then play script number. Please note that the Iron Clad Agreement founder Julia Royall is citied throughout the finding aid as Julia Swoyer, her name at the time.
  - Amazing American Idea Factory (Special Material) by Fonda Kurtz - ICA 4498 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Andrew Carnegie: A Documentary Drama by Steve Mackes - ICA 4499 (Folder 2)
  - Andrew Carnegie (Revised Version) by Steve Mackes et.al. - ICA 4500 (Folder 3)
  - Art/Work by Chris Blaetz - ICA 4501 (Folder 4)
  - Art/Work (Performance Script) by Chris Blaetz - ICA 4502 (Folder 5)
  - Barnum by Chris Blaetz - ICA 4503, 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Burbank by C.V. Peters - ICA 4504 (Folder 7)
  - Captain Ironclad's Moving Parts Revue by K.W. Hutton - ICA 4505 (Folder 8)
  - Dynamite! - ICA 4506 (Folder 9)
  - Eastman by Larry John Meyers et. al. - ICA 4507 (Folder 10)
  - Echoes from the Valley by Garry Lyons - ICA 4508, 1983 (Folder 11)
  - Edison by E. Garonzik et. al. - ICA 4509, 1979 (Folder 12)
  - Edison by Scott Cummings - ICA 4510, 1982 (Folder 13)
  - Father K by C.V. Peters - ICA 4511, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Father K (Acting Version) by C.V. Peters - ICA 4512, 1979 (Folder 2)
  - 57 by Two by Chris Blaetz - ICA 4513, 1979 (Folder 3)
  - Ford (Uncut Version) by Scott Cummings - ICA 4514 (Folder 4)
  - Ford (Acting Version) by Scott Cummings - ICA 4515 (Folder 5)
  - George Westinghouse (Script for Videotape) by Julia Swoyer and K.W. Hutton - ICA 4516 (Folder 6)
  - Gift to America by David Demarest - ICA 4517, March 1982 (Folder 7)
  - Gov't Owned Apples (Acting Version with Songs) - ICA 4518 (Folder 8)
  - Hasta Cuando? by Jerry James - ICA 4519, 1987-1989 (Folder 9-10)
  - Interchangeable Parts by Chris Blaetz - ICA 4520, 1980 (Folder 11)
  - Labor Trilogy, Part I: Homestead by R. Hankison - ICA 4521, 1980 (Folder 12)
  - Labor Trilogy, Part II: Depression by R. Hankison - ICA 4522, 1980 (Folder 13)
  - Labor Trilogy, Part III: Responsibility by R. Hankison - ICA 4523, 1980 (Folder 14)
  - Mr. Edison and his Amazing Invention Factories (2nd Draft) - ICA 4524, 1978 (Folder 15)
  - Mr. Guggenheim's American Dream: A Play of Fortune for the Radio by Chris Blaetz - ICA 4525 (Folder 16)
  - My Dear Sisters by James Rosenberg - ICA 4526, 1979 (Folder 17)
  - Out of This Furnace, Episode I adapted by Julia Swoyer - ICA 4527, 1977 (Folder 18)
  - Out of This Furnace, Episode II adapted by Julia Swoyer - ICA 4528 (Folder 19)
  - Out of This Furnace, Episode III adapted by Julia Swoyer -ICA 4529 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Out of This Furnace (New Version) adapted by Andy Wolk - ICA 4530, 1978 (Folder 2)
  - Out of This Furnace (New Version, Second Draft) adapted by Andy Wolk - ICA 4531 (Folder 3)
  - A Personal Narrative of the Confederacy by Mary Boykin Chesnut edited and adapted by K.L. Lewis - ICA 4532 (Folder 4)
  - The Prologue Play - ICA 4533, 1976 (Folder 5)
  - Sea-Change: The American Experience in Puerto Rico, 1928-1941 by Jerry James - ICA 4534, 1982 (Folder 6)
  - Search for Haven (First Draft) by B. Henry - ICA 4535 (Folder 7)
  - Shiver Me Timbers: A Salute to Transportation by Mark Harlow and K.W. Hutton - ICA 4536 (Folder 8)
  - Spirit of Mercy by Jack Rowley - ICA 4537 (Folder 9)
  - Toymakers by Chris Blaetz - ICA 4538, 1980 (Folder 10)
  - Virgins and Dynamos or, 'How Many Robber Barons Does It Take to Screw in a Light Bulb?' by Jerry James - ICA 4539, 1981 (Folder 11)
  - Westinghouse by Julia Swoyer and K.W. Hutton - ICA 4540, 1976 (Folder 12)